# Zain A. Malik

# Zackwilliams093@gmail.com +92 - 315 - 540 - 4725

https://www.linkedin.com/in/zain-ali-330624121/

#### **SUMMARY**

Senior HR Professional with an established track record of identifying and onboarding top-Notch talent. Effective in both proactive and reactionary environments with an ability to work well with people at any level Develops long-term relationships while building reliable talent pipelines with integrity

Over 11 years of progressive experience in sourcing, screening, interviewing, hiring and managing technical professionals at all levels. Recognized leader and innovator who bring extensive experience in the areas of recruiting, sales, operations management and creating unique customer and candidate experiences.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Sargodha University, St. Marry's College, R.W.P, PK

2012-2015

- Masters of Business Administration
- Concentrations: HRM: Cumulative GPA: 3.6

#### TRACCERT - CANADA

2018

• HCM Analytics (Certified)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Customer Success Solutions (Pvt) Limited**

Feb. 2018 – Present

Manager HR & Admin

- Advising on pay and other issues, including promotion and benefits; administer payroll and maintain staff records.
- Ensures planning, monitoring and appraisal of employee work results by training managers to coach and discipline employees.
- Developing HR planning strategies with line managers by considering immediate and long-term staff requirements.
- Maintains the work structure by updating job requirements and job descriptions for all positions.
- Maintains employee benefits programs and inform employees of benefits by studying and assessing benefit needs and trends.
- Ensures legal compliance by monitoring and implementing applicable human resource federal and state requirements.
- Monitor key HR metrics & Revamping of Recruitment Process.

**KeepTruckin** Jan, 2017 - Feb, 2018

## Lead HR

- Performing full Recruitment life cycle & on-boarding procedure Onshore/Offshore for both Technical & Non-Technical roles (PK, USA & Philippines).
- Develop pipelines of potential candidates Through Job Boards and social sites (LinkedIn, Monster, Indeed, Rozee.pk and Mustakbil.com).
- Reviewing, auditing, and verifying monthly benefit invoices.
- Lead employer branding initiatives.
- Maintains employee benefits programs and inform employees of benefits by studying and assessing benefit needs and trends
- Recommending benefit programs to management.
- Directing the processing of benefit claims.
- Obtaining and evaluating benefit contract bids.
- Resolving employee grievances, counselling employees and supervisors.
- Using Boolean search string, X-Ray technique and Wild-Card techniques to search the most relevant candidates from LinkedIn & Monster.
- Maintaining applicant tracking system (ATS Lever) HRIS, requisitions and job boards posting keeping the hiring manager up-to-date throughout the process.

Virtelligence Sep, 2016 - Jan, 2017

Recruitment Consultant

• Performing full Recruitment life cycle & on-boarding procedure Onshore/Offshore for both Technical & Non-Technical roles (PK, USA & Philippines).

- Develop pipelines of potential candidates Through Job Boards and social sites (LinkedIn, Monster, Indeed, Rozee.pk and Mustakbil.com).
- Reviewing, auditing, and verifying monthly benefit invoices.
- Lead employer branding initiatives.
- Maintains employee benefits programs and inform employees of benefits by studying and assessing benefit needs and trends
- Using Boolean search string, X-Ray technique and Wild-Card techniques to search the most relevant candidates from LinkedIn & Monster.

**Right Jobs.pk** Jan, 2016 - Sep, 2016

Acting Manager Recruitment

- Create pool of candidates through social media sites i.e. Facebook, twitter, LinkedIn & Google+. For Technical & Non-Technical Roles.
- Shortlisting candidates through prescreening Calls.
- Conduct in person interviews for Right jobs.pk.
- Accomplishes HR and organization mission by completing related results as needed.
- Establishes recruiting requirements by studying organization plans and objectives; meeting with Clients to discuss needs.

## **People Source international**

Dec, 2011 -Dec, 2015

Manager HR & Admin

- Maintains management guidelines by preparing, updating, and recommending human resource policies and procedures.
- Maintain records of personnel-related data (payroll, personal information, leaves, turnover rates etc.) in both paper and the database.
- Maintains office services by organizing office operations and procedures, preparing payroll; controlling Correspondence; designing filing systems; reviewing and approving supply requisitions; assigning and monitoring clerical functions.
- Ensure HR support to Onshore/Offshore operations and ensure recruitment within defined timeline. Recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training Onshore/Offshore employees (PK, USA & Philippines).
- Scheduling management conferences with employees; hearing and resolving employee grievances; counselling employees and supervisors.

J – Telemarketing

Mar, 2008 - Nov, 2011

**HR** Coordinator

- Maintain records of personnel-related data (payroll, personal information, leaves, turnover rates etc.) in both paper and the database.
- Support the recruitment/hiring process by full recruitment life Cycle, on-boarding and update records with newbies.
- Schedule meetings, interviews, HR events etc., maintain the team's agenda and submit reports on general HR activity.
- Handling employee's issues & queries regarding company's policies & procedures.

#### **SKILLS & LANGUAGE**

**Skills:** Microsoft Office • CRM • ATS • Boolean Search• Communication

Language: Urdu • English • Punjabi